<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chris Hua</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Chris Hua</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-hyperscale</title>
      <link>/posts/post-hyperscale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/post-hyperscale/</guid>
      <description>Brought to you by the power of crowds.
Sandwiches and imperial warfare When I studied abroad in Belgium, my favorite lunch spot was a small sandwich shop run by an affable old Tunisian man. He and his shop had almost legendary status among the exchange students; perhaps since he was one of the few who enjoyed speaking English, or was it the rumor that he was a TV chef in Italy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook&#39;s &#39;Fan Subscriptions&#39;</title>
      <link>/posts/facebook-subscriptions-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/facebook-subscriptions-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Or, how I learned to stop worrying and love the network.
Facebook reached out to offer Hard Drive early access to a &amp;quot;fan subscription&amp;quot; product. I asked my editors about it and the complete distrust amongst our team was kinda funny. We read through the terms and found a couple things that were hilarious when compared to Patreon&amp;#39;s 5%.
&amp;mdash; Matt Saincome (@MattSaincome) February 26, 2019  Now this is pretty interesting!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscriptions as price discrimination</title>
      <link>/posts/price-discrimination-subscriptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/price-discrimination-subscriptions/</guid>
      <description>TLDR  There are two types of subscriptions, those focused on the platform and those focused on the creators you&amp;rsquo;re supporting. Creator-focused subscriptions can be part of an extremely effective growth loop, with network effects and viewer lock-in. The most sophisticated subscription-based models are also the most efficient forms of price discrimination we&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen, where the subscriptions further the network effects and can both create and capture enormous amounts of value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Excel</title>
      <link>/posts/on-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/on-excel/</guid>
      <description>I wrote about why banks use Excel and why their workbooks are insane.
Perhaps a bit more interestingly, I also wrote about why switching to R, despite Wharton&amp;rsquo;s best efforts, isn&amp;rsquo;t going to make bankers write clean, accesible code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>n=1 year in data: Ben Jiang</title>
      <link>/posts/data-science-1-year-ben-jiang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/data-science-1-year-ben-jiang/</guid>
      <description>Interviewed 16 October 2018. Lightly edited.
 
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in being profiled, drop me a line! I&amp;rsquo;m interested in speaking to early-mid career data scientists (hence, n=1 year).
What do you do?
I&amp;rsquo;m a data scientist at KeyMe.
Our key value prop is in the tech, e.g. deep learning, which we use to scan keys and model what the output should be.
What did you study in school?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to the Metal</title>
      <link>/posts/going-to-the-metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/going-to-the-metal/</guid>
      <description>A year and a half ago I rebooted this blog using R&amp;rsquo;s Blogdown and Hugo. I thought at the time that this was a good choice, because it let me use a static site generator (aka just write Markdown), while still offering syntactic sugar and scaffolding. &amp;ldquo;Batteries included,&amp;rdquo; if you would.
The two big reasons I spent a day migrating to a raw metal Hugo installation:
 The compile and deploy process that was hacked together to work with R and Travis broke on me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The two types of data</title>
      <link>/posts/the-two-types-of-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-two-types-of-data/</guid>
      <description>Basically nothing I learned about data from school carried over when I got a data science job in industry.
The overwhelming of data which we collect in industrial data applications (by which, I do mean tech applications at scale) is log data. Most of what we work with in school (or outside of large tech companies) is not that. Typically, we&amp;rsquo;ll work with log data or metadata.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll cover what that data model looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python-Markdown Bootstrap Styling Extension</title>
      <link>/posts/python-markdown-bootstrap-styling-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/python-markdown-bootstrap-styling-extension/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a small extension for the Python-Markdown library which adds Bootstrap 4.0 styling to images and tables generated by the generator, available on GitHub.
Call this extension towards the end of your extension stack; it simply adds class=&#39;img-fluid&#39; to &amp;lt;img&amp;gt; tags and class=&#39;table table-striped&#39; to &amp;lt;table&amp;gt; tags. This extension probably isn&amp;rsquo;t life-changing and it is probably also under-tested (in particular, there is no support for Python 2.7 which I don&amp;rsquo;t use and don&amp;rsquo;t intend to support).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing between data science offers</title>
      <link>/posts/choosing-between-data-science-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/choosing-between-data-science-teams/</guid>
      <description>Not all data science roles are created equal. Everyone will tell you that &amp;ldquo;data scientists&amp;rdquo; as a role play varying parts in different companies, but how can you choose between different teams?
Some heuristics I found useful: * % of employees that are data
* are people promoted from within * investments in data infra (eg how long does it take to get experiment results)
* data culture - who does data report to in management?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science for College Students - Courses</title>
      <link>/posts/data-science-for-college-students-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/data-science-for-college-students-courses/</guid>
      <description>Giving advice to be one of the hardest things somebody can do, and yet people ask for it at an alarming rate. Perhaps the best way to start, then, is with a reminder that life is hard and it&amp;rsquo;s okay to not know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing. Your peers will pretend that they have everything figured out, and they will say as much, but know that you&amp;rsquo;re not seeing their own struggles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ice Cream Man</title>
      <link>/posts/the-ice-cream-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-ice-cream-man/</guid>
      <description>The first story Ellen Pao told was about a law firm partner who stood outside a female lawyer&amp;rsquo;s office everyday after lunch, licking an ice cream cone while staring at her. Management&amp;rsquo;s response to these instances of sexism were invariably dismissive, e.g. “you should be flattered he&amp;rsquo;s interested in you,” or “it&amp;rsquo;s just one weird guy, but overall it&amp;rsquo;s not that bad, right?” The result is an environment that views sexism as the product of just one bad apple, but it&amp;rsquo;s instead the product of a bad system: one which condones and encourages “boys club” behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Hume on Work-Life Balance</title>
      <link>/posts/david-hume-on-work-life-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/david-hume-on-work-life-balance/</guid>
      <description>Most fortunately it happens, that since reason is incapable of dispelling these clouds, nature herself suffices to that purpose, and cures me of this philosophical melancholy and delirium, either by relaxing this bent of mind, or by some avocation, and lively impression of my senses, which obliterate all these chimeras. I dine, I play a game of backgammon, I converse, and am merry with my friends; and when after three or four hours’ amusement, I would return to these speculations, they appear so cold, and strained, and ridiculous, that I cannot find in my heart to enter into them any farther.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a data scientist at Quora, passionate about data, helping others, and eating noodles. At Quora, I am on the Ads data science team. Previously, I was a data science intern at Airbnb and at Expedia.
I graduated from Wharton, majoring in statistics and finance, where I was heavily involved with the statistics and data science communities on campus. I love to hike and cook, and am just as comfortable on top of a mountain as in my cramped kitchen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging from Rstudio</title>
      <link>/posts/blogging-from-rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/blogging-from-rstudio/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been in the back of my head to remake my blog and start posting again. I&amp;rsquo;ve had some great conversations about data science (and other things too!) but now have many thoughts to put down on paper/code.
My last iteration was based on Jekyll and I think had some early iteration of blogdown. This new iteration runs with blogdown and Hugo.
The transition was very easy: copy-paste the .Rmd source files, reinstall packages for these files I haven&amp;rsquo;t touched in ages, and then run.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>