<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>articles on Chris Hua</title>
    <link>/categories/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in articles on Chris Hua</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the untimely demise of Deadspin</title>
      <link>/posts/lessons-from-deadspin-rip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lessons-from-deadspin-rip/</guid>
      <description>This is an adapted version of a memo I wrote previously.
Deadspin was a &amp;ldquo;sports blog&amp;rdquo; that was part of the Gawker family. The sites have been very popular and simultaneously very controversial, in large part due to their posts which spoke truth to power. (A less generous take would be that they were unruly rabble rousers who stuck their noses where they didn&amp;rsquo;t belong). There is a saga that involves Peter Thiel which is easy to find more details on, and which I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to comment on; suffice to say, the media org has been bought and sold multiple times over the last few years and is currently owned by a private equity firm, probably looking to squeeze some scraps of advertising revenue from the firm while they still can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-hyperscale</title>
      <link>/posts/post-hyperscale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/post-hyperscale/</guid>
      <description>Brought to you by the power of crowds.
Sandwiches and imperial warfare When I studied abroad in Belgium, my favorite lunch spot was a small sandwich shop run by an affable old Tunisian man. He and his shop had almost legendary status among the exchange students; perhaps since he was one of the few who enjoyed speaking English, or was it the rumor that he was a TV chef in Italy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook&#39;s &#39;Fan Subscriptions&#39;</title>
      <link>/posts/facebook-subscriptions-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/facebook-subscriptions-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Or, how I learned to stop worrying and love the network.
Facebook reached out to offer Hard Drive early access to a &amp;quot;fan subscription&amp;quot; product. I asked my editors about it and the complete distrust amongst our team was kinda funny. We read through the terms and found a couple things that were hilarious when compared to Patreon&amp;#39;s 5%.
&amp;mdash; Matt Saincome (@MattSaincome) February 26, 2019  Now this is pretty interesting!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscriptions as price discrimination</title>
      <link>/posts/price-discrimination-subscriptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/price-discrimination-subscriptions/</guid>
      <description>TLDR  There are two types of subscriptions, those focused on the platform and those focused on the creators you&amp;rsquo;re supporting. Creator-focused subscriptions can be part of an extremely effective growth loop, with network effects and viewer lock-in. The most sophisticated subscription-based models are also the most efficient forms of price discrimination we&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen, where the subscriptions further the network effects and can both create and capture enormous amounts of value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The two types of data</title>
      <link>/posts/the-two-types-of-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-two-types-of-data/</guid>
      <description>Basically nothing I learned about data from school carried over when I got a data science job in industry.
The overwhelming of data which we collect in industrial data applications (by which, I do mean tech applications at scale) is log data. Most of what we work with in school (or outside of large tech companies) is not that. Typically, we&amp;rsquo;ll work with log data or metadata.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll cover what that data model looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing between data science offers</title>
      <link>/posts/choosing-between-data-science-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/choosing-between-data-science-teams/</guid>
      <description>Not all data science roles are created equal. Everyone will tell you that &amp;ldquo;data scientists&amp;rdquo; as a role play varying parts in different companies, but how can you choose between different teams?
Some heuristics I found useful: * % of employees that are data
* are people promoted from within * investments in data infra (eg how long does it take to get experiment results)
* data culture - who does data report to in management?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>