<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>articles on Chris Hua</title>
    <link>/categories/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in articles on Chris Hua</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscriptions as price discrimination</title>
      <link>/posts/price-discrimination-subscriptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/price-discrimination-subscriptions/</guid>
      <description>TLDR  There are two types of subscriptions, those focused on the platform and those focused on the creators you&amp;rsquo;re supporting. Creator-focused subscriptions can be part of an extremely effective growth loop, with network effects and viewer lock-in. The most sophisticated subscription-based models are also the most efficient forms of price discrimination we&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen, where the subscriptions further the network effects and can both create and capture enormous amounts of value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The two types of data</title>
      <link>/posts/the-two-types-of-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-two-types-of-data/</guid>
      <description>Basically nothing I learned about data from school carried over when I got a data science job in industry.
The overwhelming of data which we collect in industrial data applications (by which, I do mean tech applications at scale) is log data. Most of what we work with in school (or outside of large tech companies) is not that. Typically, we&amp;rsquo;ll work with log data or metadata.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll cover what that data model looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing between data science offers</title>
      <link>/posts/choosing-between-data-science-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/choosing-between-data-science-teams/</guid>
      <description>Not all data science roles are created equal. Everyone will tell you that &amp;ldquo;data scientists&amp;rdquo; as a role play varying parts in different companies, but how can you choose between different teams?
Some heuristics I found useful: * % of employees that are data
* are people promoted from within * investments in data infra (eg how long does it take to get experiment results)
* data culture - who does data report to in management?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>