<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>startups on Chris Hua</title>
    <link>/tags/startups/</link>
    <description>Recent content in startups on Chris Hua</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/startups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-hyperscale</title>
      <link>/posts/post-hyperscale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/post-hyperscale/</guid>
      <description>Brought to you by the power of crowds.
Sandwiches and imperial warfare When I studied abroad in Belgium, my favorite lunch spot was a small sandwich shop run by an affable old Tunisian man. He and his shop had almost legendary status among the exchange students; perhaps since he was one of the few who enjoyed speaking English, or was it the rumor that he was a TV chef in Italy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook&#39;s &#39;Fan Subscriptions&#39;</title>
      <link>/posts/facebook-subscriptions-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/facebook-subscriptions-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Or, how I learned to stop worrying and love the network.
Facebook reached out to offer Hard Drive early access to a &amp;quot;fan subscription&amp;quot; product. I asked my editors about it and the complete distrust amongst our team was kinda funny. We read through the terms and found a couple things that were hilarious when compared to Patreon&amp;#39;s 5%.
&amp;mdash; Matt Saincome (@MattSaincome) February 26, 2019  Now this is pretty interesting!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscriptions as price discrimination</title>
      <link>/posts/price-discrimination-subscriptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/price-discrimination-subscriptions/</guid>
      <description>TLDR  There are two types of subscriptions, those focused on the platform and those focused on the creators you&amp;rsquo;re supporting. Creator-focused subscriptions can be part of an extremely effective growth loop, with network effects and viewer lock-in. The most sophisticated subscription-based models are also the most efficient forms of price discrimination we&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen, where the subscriptions further the network effects and can both create and capture enormous amounts of value.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>