<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notes on Chris Hua</title>
    <link>/categories/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in notes on Chris Hua</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Excel</title>
      <link>/posts/on-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/on-excel/</guid>
      <description>I wrote about why banks use Excel and why their workbooks are insane.
Perhaps a bit more interestingly, I also wrote about why switching to R, despite Wharton&amp;rsquo;s best efforts, isn&amp;rsquo;t going to make bankers write clean, accesible code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to the Metal</title>
      <link>/posts/going-to-the-metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/going-to-the-metal/</guid>
      <description>A year and a half ago I rebooted this blog using R&amp;rsquo;s Blogdown and Hugo. I thought at the time that this was a good choice, because it let me use a static site generator (aka just write Markdown), while still offering syntactic sugar and scaffolding. &amp;ldquo;Batteries included,&amp;rdquo; if you would.
The two big reasons I spent a day migrating to a raw metal Hugo installation:
 The compile and deploy process that was hacked together to work with R and Travis broke on me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Hume on Work-Life Balance</title>
      <link>/posts/david-hume-on-work-life-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/david-hume-on-work-life-balance/</guid>
      <description>Most fortunately it happens, that since reason is incapable of dispelling these clouds, nature herself suffices to that purpose, and cures me of this philosophical melancholy and delirium, either by relaxing this bent of mind, or by some avocation, and lively impression of my senses, which obliterate all these chimeras. I dine, I play a game of backgammon, I converse, and am merry with my friends; and when after three or four hours’ amusement, I would return to these speculations, they appear so cold, and strained, and ridiculous, that I cannot find in my heart to enter into them any farther.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging from Rstudio</title>
      <link>/posts/blogging-from-rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/blogging-from-rstudio/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been in the back of my head to remake my blog and start posting again. I&amp;rsquo;ve had some great conversations about data science (and other things too!) but now have many thoughts to put down on paper/code.
My last iteration was based on Jekyll and I think had some early iteration of blogdown. This new iteration runs with blogdown and Hugo.
The transition was very easy: copy-paste the .Rmd source files, reinstall packages for these files I haven&amp;rsquo;t touched in ages, and then run.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>